<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sopresas on Unorthodoxdev</title>
    <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/sopresas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sopresas on Unorthodoxdev</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 18:26:44 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/sopresas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gorilla Balls</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/sopresas/gorilla-balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 18:26:44 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/sopresas/gorilla-balls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 cup packed brown sugar. 1/2 c. butter (cubed). 2 tubes (12 oz each) refigerated biscuts. 1/2 c. sugar. 1 tbsp ground cinnamon. 1 package (8oz) cream cheese, cut into 20 cubes. Directions In a small microwave-safe bowl, heat brown sugar and butter on high for one minute or until sugar is disolved. Set aside.&#xA;Flatten each biscuit into a 3 inch circle.&#xA;Place cream cheese cube in center. Push the sides of the biscuit around cream cheese and form into ball so biscuit is wrapped all around cream cheese.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cowboy Cookies</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/sopresas/cowboy-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 14:06:29 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/sopresas/cowboy-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 2 cups flour 1/2 tsp baking powder 1 tsp baking soda 1/2 tsp salt 1/2 cup butter 1/2 cup vegetable oil 1 cup backed light brown sugar 1 cup white sugar 2 eggs 1 tsp vanilla extract 2 cups quick cooking oats 1 cup semi-sweet chocolate chips or other mix-ins Directions Preheat oven to 350 F Mix flour, baking powder, baking soda, and salt together, set aside Cream butter, oil, and sugars together until light and fluffy Add eggs and vanilla and cream again Add oats and flour mixture, mix until almost combined Add mix-ins, mix until just combined Drop by spoonfuls onto ungreased baking sheet, bake 10-12 minutes</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bannana Bread</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/sopresas/bannana-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 13:24:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/sopresas/bannana-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 3 1/2 cups of sifted all purpose flour 3 tsp baking powder 1 tsp salt 1 tsp baking soda 2 cups of mashed ripe bananas 2 tsp of lemon juice 3/4 cups of shortening 1 1/2 cup of sugar 3 eggs 3/4 cups of milk 1/2 chopped walnuts or pecans Directions Sift together flour, baking powder, salt, and baking soda, combine bananas and lemon juice. Mix well.&#xA;Cream together shortening and sugar in a bowl with electric mixer medium speed until fluffy.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
