<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dinner on Unorthodoxdev</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dinner on Unorthodoxdev</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 11:31:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Noodle Soupless (Slow Cooker)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/chicken-noodle-soupless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 11:31:24 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/chicken-noodle-soupless/</guid>
      <description>Notice, that this recipe, requires roughly 7 hours to complete, most of which are waiting on the slowcooker.&#xA;Ingredients Defrosted Chicken Breasts or Thighs (thighs preferred or chicken breasts cut into strips). 2 cans of corn, 3 or fresh cobs. 1 can of cut carrots, 2 fresh carrots. 3 chile poblano peppers. 1/4 cup of cream cheese. Parmesan cheese. (Optional) Mozzarella. Directions Note because this recipie takes so long, its ideal to start this at home on my lunch break, or place the chicken in the morning on low, though ive never tested leaving the crockpot on all day cooking like that, I imagine it should be fine :)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goulash</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/goulash/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 15:42:37 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/goulash/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1lb of ground beef. 1 onion (preferably yellow or red). Tomatoes. Bell Peppers. Canned tomato sauce. Noodles (preferably macaroni). 1/2 Cup water. 2-4 cloves of garlic. Oregano Basil Crushed Red Pepper Red Wine (Optional) Instructions Dice the onion and garlic. Throw them both into a large soup pot on medium, medium high. Drop a splash of oil. (you dont need alot of oil because shortly youll be adding greasy beef to the mix.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enchiladas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/enchiladas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 15:41:38 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/enchiladas/</guid>
      <description>Enchiladas are traditionally served stuffed with cheese or potatoes, but in america are commonly found stuffed with chicken. Realistically you can use what ever you want, ive even had carne asada enchiladas&amp;hellip;&#xA;Ingredients Chiles Guajillo Chiles Ancho Garlic Cloves Oregano Salt and pepper Corn Tortillas Queso Fresco Potaoes (optional) Chicken Breast (optional) Cebollya Blanca Vegetable oil Lettuce Sour Cream Instructions Toast all of your chiles on a open flame or pan until hot, maybe burnt.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Mack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/chicken-mack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 15:31:25 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/chicken-mack/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 16 oz. box spiral noodles or elbow noodles. 1 25 oz. bag of chicken strips. 1 pack of bacon strips (optional). Salt and Pepper. Basil. Cheese Sauce 1 stick butter. 2 cups heavy cream. 1/2 cup shredded parmesan cheese. 1 cup mozzarella cheese, freshly shredded. 3/4 cup colby jack cheese, freshly shredded. 2-3 cloves of garlic, minced. Chopped fresh basil. Instructions Begin preheating your oven and prepping a tray to cook your chicken tenders on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tinga</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/tinga/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 13:57:24 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/tinga/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Large Yellow Onion. Oil. Stewed Tomatoes (Can be home made or from a can). Chipotle peppers in adobo sauce. Tostadas Sour cream Chicken breasts (Optional) Pineapple Directions In a large pot, begin to boil your chicken. Once your chicken is fully cooked, remove it from the water and allow time for it to cool. Once cool, begin to shred the chicken by hand.&#xA;While the pot of chicken is boiling you could begin to add your tomatoes and chipotle peppers in (if raw and not from a can) to begin boiling, or add it to its own pot and boil that way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andrea&#39;s Chilli Recipe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/andreas-chili-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 13:24:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/andreas-chili-recipe/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 lb ground beef 1 medium onion, chopped 1 green pepper chopped 2 stalks of celery, chopped. 1 can black beans rinsed and drained. 1 can dark red kidney beans rinsed and drained 1 can garbonzo beans, rinsed and drained. 1 can kidney beans in chili sauce (do not drain or rinse these) 1 can corn rinsed and drained 2 cans diced tomatoes Directions Brown beef in skillet over medium heat until no longer pink.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taco Salad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/taco-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 13:24:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/dinner/taco-salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 head of lettuce, shredded 1 medium onion, chopped 1 lb hamburger browned 2 cups of cheddar cheese shredded 3 medium tomatoes, chopped 1 bag dorites crushed 1/2 to 1 bottle Western French Dressing (8 oz) Directions In a large bowl, layer each ingredient strating with lettuce and ending with tomatoes. Toss with western dressing and crushed doritos just before serving.&#xA;If you are planning for left overs, allow guests to add the doritos and dressing on their own to prevent any soggynonsens.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
