<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Unorthodoxdev</title>
    <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Unorthodoxdev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 20:46:09 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://unorthodoxdev.net/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Internet Addiction and Cell Phone Usage</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2024-02-26-internet-addiction-and-cell-phone-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 20:46:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2024-02-26-internet-addiction-and-cell-phone-usage/</guid>
      <description>The below question came from a class discussion, and I really enjoyed it because it is something that I have recently been doing quite a bit of research on personally. While I did respond to the discussion, it was not in the length that I would have wanted. So I summarized the two paragraphs here and shared it with class. Otherwise, my personal response is as follows below.
Do you think using cell phones too much is bad for our physical or mental health?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Pedagogy of the Oppressed</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2024-02-23-notes-on-pedagogy-of-the-oppressed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 23:59:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2024-02-23-notes-on-pedagogy-of-the-oppressed/</guid>
      <description>As a warning, Pedagogy of the Oppressed is a deeply theoretical text, and at that it is a leftist text, that contains many run on and long winded paragraphs for sentences. I recommend the read to anyone who can bear it. It is a 180 pages of though provoking statements. Below are my thoughts on the text as I read through it…
To start, what is a Pedagogy? As defined by the Merriam-Webster dictionary, a Pedagogy “the art, science, or profession of teaching”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the network card with Netsh</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2024-02-15-manipulating-the-network-card-with-netsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 06:48:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2024-02-15-manipulating-the-network-card-with-netsh/</guid>
      <description>Recently, in an advent of troubleshooting a network issue, I had to run around and set a number of static IP&amp;rsquo;s onto devices. This being said, having to physically get up and run around a touch a number of devices can be a bit tedious.
Given you can get a remote session with each computer, you can issue the following commands using netsh.
Gathering Information Lets start by getting some information on the current device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlining Your Nvim Config</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2024-01-22-streamlining-your-nvim-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 15:34:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2024-01-22-streamlining-your-nvim-config/</guid>
      <description>I console into a number of computers daily. Many running different services etc. I also have a few different devices everywhere I go, whether it be my home PC, laptop, or work laptop etc. Along with the many devices, a good chunk of my work consists of editing text files. Most of that time spent in vim. So a decent configuration is almost a neccesity to keep my productivity up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scripting a New Install With Winget</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2024-01-22-scripting-a-new-install-with-winget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 14:05:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2024-01-22-scripting-a-new-install-with-winget/</guid>
      <description>To start, i like to routinely image my devices just to get a fresh start on them. Often, i add apps or tools that I think that I will use, that I never end up using. Most of my devices get pretty cluttered pretty quickly too so re-imaging them is a way for me to avoid data hoarding. That way, everything that I need thats important ends up backed up somewhere on a different physical device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Refactor</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2024-01-20-website-refactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 22:52:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2024-01-20-website-refactor/</guid>
      <description>For a long time, I kind of hacked this website along, by modifying the templates core files to get things to work like the favicon, avatar image etc. When I migrated from ghost, it was in the middle of semesters and I just didnt have the energy to dedicate to figuring out how the hell to use the theme. What unfortunately sucks is that the github repository tells you to do it one way, and the support documentation tells you to do it a different way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fallow Devlog 02</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-12-20-fallow-devlog-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 22:22:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-12-20-fallow-devlog-02/</guid>
      <description>Above is a screen capture of my progress made with the game fallow. A few things so far, I have no idea what I want this game to be. The best word I have for it so far is an interactive adventure. I think of those terminal story games where you must look around, explore, get into combat, loot, go back, etc. I’m not sure how this will flush out entirely but overall I am taking this as a learning experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally a Favicon</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-12-18-finally-a-favicon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 14:05:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-12-18-finally-a-favicon/</guid>
      <description>Finals are over, so you know what that means&amp;hellip; New Favicon :). Well kind of. I&amp;rsquo;ve purposely left the favicon. Deep down, I have always wanted to make the favicon a simple spiral. But unfortunately, my obession with spirals is not strong enough, nor do i think it represents this website appropriately. So as a compromise to my self, ive left the favicon blank until i find or request someone to generate a said favicon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comment Downtime 2023.11.28</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-11-28-comment-downtime-2023.11.28/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 12:29:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-11-28-comment-downtime-2023.11.28/</guid>
      <description>Today, I had an unexpected downtime of roughly 2 hours 2023.11.28 3-4 UTC. I had a Russian visiter Sunday (?) the 25th who commented essentially an ad about their website SEO skills onto the comment board. This is unfortunately the internet, and even more so a comment board where anyone can say and do anything (within the rules).
Normally I would have no real issues with what they have done, as it is not commit a crime, nor is it necessarilly disruptive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating the Challenges of Asset Inventory Management</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-11-17-navigating-the-challenges-of-asset-inventory-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 15:33:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-11-17-navigating-the-challenges-of-asset-inventory-management/</guid>
      <description>Asset Inventory Management systems present challenges for many organizations. The daily task of managing, finding, and tracking devices can be time-consuming. Various ideas emerge to simplify device tracking, such as naming devices after their serial numbers. However, this approach often provides limited insight in case of issues.
Consider the alternative of assigning meaningful names like BLD-FLASTNAME01 or lastname01—common practices to enhance clarity. Yet, challenges arise when dealing with staff changes or shared devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flush Dns on Mac</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-10-12-flush-dns-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 16:45:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-10-12-flush-dns-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>Gah, they make everything so hard. (I need to run two simple commands.) Why cant I just run one command and flush the dns on my mac? Well im sure theres a better way to do this&amp;hellip; (there is)
Welcome to flushdns(.sh)
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 #!/bin/bash # This script will clear your dns cache on your mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dont Update Nginx Without a Backup of Configs</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-10-05-dont-update-nginx-without-a-backup-of-configs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 14:58:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-10-05-dont-update-nginx-without-a-backup-of-configs/</guid>
      <description>Allrght, I did a vulnerability scan on the web server, there was something about the version of nginx installed had a flaw in it, so I went ahead and patched the nginx install. Ofcourse only because it is patch thursday and it might as well be on a list of things todo. Well, everything went smoothly; I upgraded to the latest version, refreshed the website in the browser, checked my config file, and were good to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating and Managing a SSL Cert</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-21-creating-and-managing-a-ssl-cert/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 16:39:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-21-creating-and-managing-a-ssl-cert/</guid>
      <description>This guide is intended for Ubuntu 22.04 and is intended for use with a Apache2 web server. To get started we need to make sure you have Apache2 installed, we can use grep to check. These instructions were written on a Ubuntu Server.
1 apt list --installed | grep &amp;#34;apache2&amp;#34; Next will need to allow Apache through the firewall on both http (80) and https (443). We can do so with the below command</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple File Parsing Takes Three Hours</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-21-simple-file-parsing-takes-three-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 09:53:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-21-simple-file-parsing-takes-three-hours/</guid>
      <description>NMAP really needs some kind of file output option that isnt leetcode, xml, or gibberish. I would kill for a csv output from nmap. Regardless, lets solve this problem. I chose to ues python because I figured it would be quick and easy and would take no time. I was in fact wrong; Im not quite as comfortable with python as I am with rust at this point, but thats ok.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizational Behaviour Examples</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-19-organizational-behaviour-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 17:36:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-19-organizational-behaviour-examples/</guid>
      <description>Preface In a behavioural organization class, we have an assignment to watch a movie and pick a sceene from it where we notice some organizational behaviour coming into play. Below are my awnsers to this assignment.
Organizational Behaviours in Media This clip is from the movie Free Guy. It is a movie about a bank teller, who learns that he is a non-playable character or NPC in an open-world video game, akin to GTA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to search Text files with grep</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-08-how-to-search-text-files-with-grep/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 07:55:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-08-how-to-search-text-files-with-grep/</guid>
      <description>Ever needed to find something in a directory filled with text files. Use grep. The command I enjoy to using is as follows:
1 grep -Ril &amp;#34;what the H E double hockey sticks&amp;#34; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where am i on the network?</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-07-where-am-i-on-the-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 16:51:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-07-where-am-i-on-the-network/</guid>
      <description>Ever wonder what port your connected to when plugged into a ethernet jack? Open up wireshark and apply a filter, searching for cdp or lldp traffic. That will kick back:
The switches MAC Address. The port description. The switch system name. Some information about the operating system running on the switch. Don&amp;rsquo;t see any information populating? Most likely your network admins have disabled your switches from transmitting CDP or LLDP traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vacation</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-07-vacation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 10:32:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-07-vacation/</guid>
      <description>Im back!
Ive been gone for a little while now. I went on vacation to mexico for about 21 days to visit friends. I had a blast. Everything there is vastly different than here in the states. Where I live, if you need anything other than beer you need to drive about 5-20 minutes to get whatever you need. In Druango Durango Mexico, If I need to go to the store, its about a 5 minute walk to a Ley; The equivalent of a walmart or meijers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-09-advent-of-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 15:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-09-advent-of-code/</guid>
      <description>Advent of Code is a annual set of Christmas themed programming problem that follow an advent calendar. I have heard about Advent of Code (AoC from now on) before but never committed time or resources to it.
Struggling to learn C, I decided to go through the AoC content from 2015 to current and complete each of the challenges with at a minimum, attempting to use C. The nice thing about doing the older problems, well really any problem, is that there are plenty of resources around online to help me work through and solve the problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Troubleshooting Methodology</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-09-network-troubleshooting-methodology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 14:17:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-09-network-troubleshooting-methodology/</guid>
      <description>This is a guide i&amp;rsquo;ve created with some notes I have created while working through the networking+ content. While I do plenty of networking troubleshooting experience, these instructions ensure that I STOP, and SLOWN DOWN and think about the changes. Something else I enjoy about these instructions is they force me to think more about change management. Something I need more practice with.
Gather as much information as possible. If possible, duplicate the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Things to Do</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-07-finding-things-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 09:36:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-07-finding-things-to-do/</guid>
      <description>I am the ultimate procrastinator. I can never seem to commit, or consider a project done. I have a perpetual train of thought going on when I think of projects or problems. I often wont even start a project, unless I can envision the end. Some people may see this as a good trait, being that I am able to plan the project, and goals out from start to finish instead of aimlessly working on something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In dire need of comments.</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-01-in-dire-need-of-comments./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 10:07:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-01-in-dire-need-of-comments./</guid>
      <description>I recently migrated my website from ghost blog to hugo which is a static site generator compared to the all in one package you get with ghost blog. One of the reasons I decided to make this change was honestly, I had no need for all of the many features that ghost blog provided. Something like Hugo was simple, and effective. It also allowed me to write my documents in mark down, and store the entirety of it in a git repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing a Sick 504 Page</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-27-implementing-a-sick-504-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 12:09:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-27-implementing-a-sick-504-page/</guid>
      <description>Rust takes forever to build. Im sure I could do alot better deploying the application. But who knows, maybe im doing great at deploying my [comment board](https://unorthodoxdev. net/comment) but what if there is some bug that I introduced that crashes the server 👻. What if while the server is crashed, Im at work??? Well good thing we can customize the default 504 page that nginx uses. So lets get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bloging System</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-21-new-bloging-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 10:58:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-21-new-bloging-system/</guid>
      <description>Ive migrated my website from the ghost blogging platform to hugo (go hugo, go hugo, go!). Its a little simpler and easier to manage. I also feel as though I have more controll. Currently, im using the hugo-stacked-theme as it looks the most appealing to me, and is not a massive website with insane overhead. It also comes with a indexing feature that allows me (and you ofcourse) to search my content for specific keywords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read the Damn Instructions</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-21-read-the-damn-instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 10:50:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-21-read-the-damn-instructions/</guid>
      <description>Read the damn instructions. Im working on a new project for the website, and Im trying to upload what I have to github (a simple readme nothing more).
I create an empty repository, init, add, and commit locally. Set the remote repository, and try to push to the remote&amp;hellip; And it fails? What have I done? What did I do? I have done this probably thousands of times. Where did I mess up?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghost Printers</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-20-ghost-printers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 16:03:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-20-ghost-printers/</guid>
      <description>Ive recently had an encounter with a printer that creates 100s of copies of its self within the computers printer settings. Ive spent quite a bit of time tinkering with this printer and its settings. I think I’ve come to a resolution. Overall, to recap what I did; Opening up the Regedit there were 100’s of keys associated with the Xerox printer. Typically, these registry keys are created when installing the printer and the windows printui.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MECM API</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-mecm-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 21:02:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-mecm-api/</guid>
      <description>Currently im looking into creating an application to harvest device information using the MECM API. Since I constantly have to research where the MECM Admin service has its hooks, i thought it would be a good idea to add some general information here.
The Basics The AdminService is a REST API that runs as a service, independent of the other web components in IIS on your site servers.
Service You can check the status of the service in the console under \Monitoring\Overview\System Status\Component Status - SMS_REST_PROVIDER</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tattoo</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-tattoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 21:01:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-tattoo/</guid>
      <description>Repository: https://github.com/ofgrenudo/tattoo/tree/master
Tattoo is the first complete program that I have written in rust. It consists of two parts, a library and the binary. One of the challenges I experienced when writing this application was the lack of abbility to include files outside of module&amp;rsquo;s folder that I was writing in. While I understand now why you should not do so and the kinds of compiler problems you would encounter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ci Pipelines With Rust</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-ci-pipelines-with-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 21:01:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-ci-pipelines-with-rust/</guid>
      <description>Give a man a fish, and you feed him for a day. Teach a man to fish, and you feed him for a lifetime.
CI, Continuous onus Integration allows for each member of a team to integrate their changes into the main branch, multiple times a day.
Continuous Integration allows us to tighten the feed back loop. We are less likely to go off on your own and develop for days or weeks just to find out the approach you have taken isn&amp;rsquo;t working, or isn&amp;rsquo;t approved by peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ublock Origin and More</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-ublock-origin-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 21:00:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-ublock-origin-and-more/</guid>
      <description>Everybody knows about uBlock Origin. The browser extension that blocks ads right? Well most ads. Theres often ads from social medias sites like facebook and twitter that slip through really.
Although I recently learned that uBlock has the capability to extend those block lists. The easiset way to add capabilities to your uBlock is to find these pre made lists of URLs and it should begin to block those ads for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Gardens</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-digital-gardens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 20:59:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-digital-gardens/</guid>
      <description>Outline What is a Digital Garden? A place for ideas to grow. A place for critiques. An exercise in learning in public. Learn In Public Humility. Honesty. Generate Resources that you wish you had. Work In Public Document Your Self. Document Your Steps Working In Public Forces you to Work your Metacognitive Mind. Resources What is a digital garden? https://notes.joschua.io/50+Slipbox/Digital+garden Work In Public https://nesslabs.com/work-in-public Learn In Public https://www.swyx.io/learn-in-public Pick Up What They Put Down https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting a Hostname on Linux</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-setting-a-hostname-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 20:58:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-setting-a-hostname-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>⚠️ Danger You will need administrative access to the device in question. Changing a hostname can have unintended catastrophic consequences if done without proper consideration.
A hostname is a computers human readable address that allows you to communicate with it, regardless of weather or not you know what its IP address is. Hostnames are pratcial and easy to remember. For whatever reason if you need to reset your hostname on a linux machine, you can follow the below instructions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Administration Tips and Tricks</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-linux-administration-tips-and-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 20:58:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-linux-administration-tips-and-tricks/</guid>
      <description>These notes should work on given any GNU / Linux based operating system. Although, should you run into any road blocks future me. Im sorry for lying to you :(.
Service Monitoring Services are a integral part of every operating system. How can I monitor and troubleshoot system services when things go wrong?
System Services This command in a very cute way, will display all of the services installed on your server, and then display them accordingly with + or - signs to indicate weather or not it is running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Start Menu Layouts</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-custom-start-menu-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 12:31:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-custom-start-menu-layouts/</guid>
      <description>Windows 11 and Start Menus suck. Nothing works the way Microsoft says it should unless you use Intune. So to get around it, we just copy the bin. For now I&amp;rsquo;m doing both, considering sometime in the future Microsoft might get its stuff together and allow the JSON file to work.
Start Menu Layouts Creating a new Layout On a build PC configure your new layout. run the Export-StartLayout command. Modify the StartLayout file and change the pinnedList to primaryOEMPins Copy the JSON file to C:\Users\Default\AppData\Local\Microsof\Windows\Shell Alternatively, windows holds an encrypted version of the startup file in the %LocalAppData%\Packages\Microsoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating Ghost Blog Domain Names</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-migrating-ghost-blog-domain-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 12:20:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-migrating-ghost-blog-domain-names/</guid>
      <description>Note! I have migrated away from ghost blog and now manage my site on hugo!
For some reason when I was looking up how to change [[domain names]] for my ghost blog, I kept running into recommendations that stated I should just reinstall ghost. I really don&amp;rsquo;t want to do that especially since so much content exists on this server already. It also reminded me that I probably need to take regular backups of the server anyways.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
