<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>General on Unorthodoxdev</title>
        <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/categories/general/</link>
        <description>Recent content in General on Unorthodoxdev</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 15:34:58 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://unorthodoxdev.net/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>2024.01.22 Streamlining Your Nvim Config</title>
        <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2024-01-22-2024.01.22-streamlining-your-nvim-config/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 15:34:58 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2024-01-22-2024.01.22-streamlining-your-nvim-config/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I console into a number of computers daily. Many running different services etc. I also have a few different devices everywhere I go, whether it be my home PC, laptop, or work laptop etc. Along with the many devices, a good chunk of my work consists of editing text files. Most of that time spent in vim. So a decent configuration is almost a neccesity to keep my productivity up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to keep my nvim configuration in a configs repo on github, but as time went on, every system I touched, or every update I made to the repository meant that I would have to &lt;code&gt;git pull origin&lt;/code&gt; and copy the contents into where ever the hell my nvim config folder was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, If I seperate the nvim configuration folder/files into its own repository and then clone the repository as my config, I could create an alias called &lt;code&gt;nvim-conf-update&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;git pull origin&lt;/code&gt; in my configuration folder and automatically sync all of my configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hell this could become an automated task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ofgrenudo/nvim&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;So i set out to seperate my nvim configuration.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Fallow Devlog 02</title>
        <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-12-20-fallow-devlog-02/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 22:22:22 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-12-20-fallow-devlog-02/</guid>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;620&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/SZrikhGiqQ4?si=XrCB43I7W6U3qhyi&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is a screen capture of my progress made with the game fallow. A few things so far, I have no idea what I want this game to be. The best word I have for it so far is an interactive adventure. I think of those terminal story games where you must look around, explore, get into combat, loot, go back, etc. I’m not sure how this will flush out entirely but overall I am taking this as a learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is my first time writing any kind of game, let alone any kind of game using Godot. On top of that Godot uses GDScript, which is an interpreted language similar to python (if not exactly python).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the things I talk about in the video, what do I like about it? Well mostly, so far, I really like the fact that GDScript forces you to almost work in a functional aspect. I’m not sure that I ever considered python to be a functional programming language. I also don’t have much experience with it either, so I don’t really know either way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Godot offers a C# variant that allows you to program games that way, but my biggest aversion to that, is that it feels almost Tootoo serious for what I want to do. I think so far, I’ve made the right call GDScript is flexible and has what I need to be successful in making this little game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;objectives&#34;&gt;Objectives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next few things I need to do in the game are as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Persistent Player Health and Experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete the game loop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to go back home or to town.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bloopers&#34;&gt;Bloopers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point in the development proccess, I ran into an issue setting the map. It didnt make the initial cut for the video because it was a bit of flashing between themes, but the behavior was intended. This was a great exercise of some problem solving skills and a reminder that I dont know everything. It takes breaking the problem down into smaller pieces and analyze the issues at hand, and the error presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;620&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Qk2QgM7Ob90?si=G4ZOUWJY1wiv8QJa&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Finally a Favicon</title>
        <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-12-18-finally-a-favicon/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 14:05:09 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-12-18-finally-a-favicon/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Finals are over, so you know what that means&amp;hellip; New Favicon :). Well kind of. I&amp;rsquo;ve purposely left the favicon. Deep down, I have always wanted to make the favicon a simple spiral. But unfortunately, my obession with spirals is not strong enough, nor do i think it represents this website appropriately. So as a compromise to my self, ive left the favicon blank until i find or request someone to generate a said favicon. Well, today is the day. Browsing itch.io I came across a pixel planet generate (oh em ghee, i had to check this out) and well it does exactly what it said it would. And im in love. And so i set out on a quest to generate a million planets until I found the one that I wanted. You can find and play with the same exact program I was here &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://deep-fold.itch.io/pixel-planet-generator&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://deep-fold.itch.io/pixel-planet-generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reminded me of an old program that I made a while ago, where I was experimenting with noise maps, and the rasterization of said noise map. The fun part about this experiment of mine was that it had three decimal points to it, and each decimal point was translated into a RGB color code at some point. Making at times this really magnificent image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, what are our candidates for the favicon?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;candidate-one&#34;&gt;Candidate one&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unorthodoxdev-bucket-public.s3.amazonaws.com/earthlike-1.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;earthlike-1.gif&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I like about it? Its simple, the clouds are nice and it is somewhat land, somewhat clouds. There is unfortunately way tooooo much land to be a close representation of earth. But overall I like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;candidate-two&#34;&gt;Candidate two&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unorthodoxdev-bucket-public.s3.amazonaws.com/earthlike-2.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;earthlike-2&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably the most similar to earth, although my only dislike of this is that it probably represents pangea better than it does the modernday continents. Which is fine with me either way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;candidate-three&#34;&gt;Candidate three&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unorthodoxdev-bucket-public.s3.amazonaws.com/saturnlike-1.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;saturnlike-1&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like this one, It does a good job at displaying the ring around the planet, and the colors are more of my style. Overall this is very high up in the ranking list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what-will-i-pick&#34;&gt;So what will I pick?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, to be honest with you I like each of these individually, but after experimenting with each of these I think that I prefer candidate two as it gives the most texture in the small favicon view. Overall though, it was nice to see the program and shader written in godot, and I got a neat favicon out of it. Win Win :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Comment Downtime 2023.11.28</title>
        <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-11-28-comment-downtime-2023.11.28/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 12:29:55 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-11-28-comment-downtime-2023.11.28/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I had an unexpected downtime of roughly 2 hours 2023.11.28 3-4 UTC. I had a Russian visiter Sunday (?) the 25th who commented essentially an ad about their website SEO skills onto the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.unorthodoxdev.net/comment/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;comment board&lt;/a&gt;. This is &lt;em&gt;unfortunately&lt;/em&gt; the internet, and even more so a &lt;em&gt;comment board&lt;/em&gt; where anyone can say and do anything (within the rules).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally I would have no real issues with what they have done, as it is not commit a crime, nor is it necessarilly disruptive. But they did happen to comment three times, each time the same thing without any kind of variation. This was cause for concern&amp;hellip;. (im joking). But as a webadmin, I can do whatever the hell I want and censor whatever kind of things I want to censor, so why not exercise my webadmin rights and change the visibility of the excess comments and then leave a curdious note to the user about why I had to mark their notes as hidden? Naturally, you have to hide the comment on production right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heres where everything starts going down hill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to begin by running the command &lt;code&gt;sqlite3 comments.db&lt;/code&gt;. That is where i messed up first. I should have made a backup of the database. Its prone to human error (me, its prone to me, absolutely fucking it up, im the problem).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then, was sitting in the console and it has been so long since ive worked on this project, I have no idea what the hell kind of comannds I need to run to view the database scheema, I know I could look at the source code, but curiosity got me and what if i didnt have access to the source code? well you can run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34; data-lang=&#34;sql&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;schema&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;ON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;schema&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;and it spits out the schema used to create the database. Cool, ive got my column variable types, and ive got the id from the comment board. So i need to just set the visibility to 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boom, I do that with the following command, &lt;code&gt;UPDATE comments SET visible = 0 WHERE id = &amp;quot;&amp;lt;id_goes_here&amp;gt;&amp;quot;;&lt;/code&gt; it works. I do it for the other post i want to get rid of. And I update the poorly named &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ofgrenudo/comment.unorthodoxdev.net/commit/830d376b8c9eb9ef29aeda649309483033b16ed1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;code&gt;slqite-commands.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; file with the command i used. Boom bam bow, whenever this happens again, i&amp;rsquo;m a prepared web admin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I type my relatively polite message up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello MikhailRS, thank you for visting the site. This is by far the internet, you are welcome to do whatever you want to my site. I can simply destroy this website and start it up again. But please, in the future, do not repeat your post as it is breaking the rules (no spam) as listed in the above headers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I appreciate your feed back as you have made a few things apparent to me, One the rules should be numbered in an ordered list so i can refer to them as numbers and not by &amp;ldquo;the rules&amp;rdquo;. Two, when I hide a comment, it still rederns in the html as a comment_ div. I will need to fix that sometime soon, its looking like a bug that will get resolved in probably 5 weeks as finals is coming up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you my friend :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Translate, do your thang:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Здравствуйте, МихаилРС, спасибо, что посетили сайт. Это, безусловно, Интернет, вы можете делать на моем сайте все, что захотите. Я могу просто уничтожить этот сайт и запустить его заново. Но, пожалуйста, в будущем не повторяйте свой пост, поскольку он нарушает правила (без спама), перечисленные в заголовках выше.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Хотя я ценю вашу обратную связь, поскольку вы объяснили мне некоторые вещи, во-первых, правила должны быть пронумерованы в упорядоченном списке, чтобы я мог называть их числами, а не «правилами». Во-вторых, когда я скрываю комментарий, он все равно отображается в HTML как div comment_. Мне нужно будет это исправить в ближайшее время, это похоже на ошибку, которая будет исправлена, вероятно, через 5 недель, когда приближается финал.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Спасибо, мой друг :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And post it  to the comment board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then try to push the changes to the git repository and run into an authentication error. Why is that? maybe its because I don&amp;rsquo;t have my ssh keys on the server. Why is that? because its publicly accessible and prone to Russian dudes poking my server. And why don&amp;rsquo;t i want my ssh keys on the server? because they are used to authenticate to my GitHub. I at some point used my brain in this convoluted process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No biggie, let me just git pull origin and uncommit all of these stupid changes. LOL. it overwrote the database. All comments lost, Im not back at the tracked testing version of &lt;code&gt;comments.db&lt;/code&gt;. About 6 months worth of commenting gold lost in the wind. Only to be held in my memory. This can never happen again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I go on a bug fixing protocol making rampage, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ofgrenudo/comment.unorthodoxdev.net/commit/0d2f47ceeaa5a3707381337f36b96ff5ae91b9cf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;I resolve the bug causing empty divs to show when i hide a comment&lt;/a&gt; and fix a number of spelling errors along the way. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ofgrenudo/comment.unorthodoxdev.net/blob/df2c54671ded81ddad69100df2e3d53f6426e8b9/backup.sh&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;I also create a backup solution to never do this again&lt;/a&gt;. And with that, I hopefully never make changes on prod again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To over view heres a list of ways that I fucked up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make changes on prod.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit changes on prod.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roll back changes on prod.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t back changes up on prod.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your database in the same folder as your source (shhh we didn&amp;rsquo;t talk about this).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, the kind stranger &lt;strong&gt;MikhailRS&lt;/strong&gt; taught me a few things though. List your rules as numbers so you can refer to them as Rule #4 instead of Rulez. You also pointed out a bug in the templating that I had. Finally, you also reminded me that I need to create a admin panel of sorts to hide comments lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, there is my report on what the went wrong, November 28th, 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Simple File Parsing Takes Three Hours</title>
        <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-21-simple-file-parsing-takes-three-hours/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 09:53:13 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-21-simple-file-parsing-takes-three-hours/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;NMAP really needs some kind of file output option that isnt leetcode, xml, or gibberish. I would kill for a csv output from nmap. Regardless, lets solve this problem. I chose to ues python because I figured it would be quick and easy and would take no time. I was in fact wrong; Im not quite as comfortable with python as I am with rust at this point, but thats ok. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ofgrenudo/noparser/blob/main/noparser.py&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;It took about 2-3 hours to build and test a simple program&lt;/a&gt;. This stupid script, took a little over 40 minutes trying to figure out how to build a stupid CLI interface and I immediately realized I miss rusts built in fail handling. Your telling me that I have to try, except &lt;strong&gt;everything???&lt;/strong&gt;. Oh well it doesnt matter anyways this doesnt actually compile down to machine code there are no assembly jumps or calls, lets just do it&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God I hate this I decided to just cave and research a few CLI libraries and landed on plac, which has some very terrible documentation. For example, they do not explicilty provide a way for you to accept a file path or string lol. I just had to play around with the program until I found something that works, but this library could literally kill for some more english in the documentation. After I got that going it was easy peasy lemon squeezy. Except, when you error out, it doesnt really tell you why if your in a try catch loop. So I have to effectively comment out the try catch loop, and lower my code a indentation bracket figure out what the hell is breaking my code, just to realize I forgot to pass a variable to a function but was referencing it anyways&amp;hellip;. Another downside to try catch. Why the hell is my program failing. Otherwise, this program is less than 40 lines without all the stupid comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I could think about was those intro to CS classes in college where your just recycling CSV parsing code over and over again for a whole semester and building stupid text UI. All those hours of code, ammounted to a waste of three hours at work trying to get a CSV. But was it worth the three hours one might ask? well, the fact that I can run and scan the network using NMAP, and imemdiately convert it to a csv file to later open in XSLX or another stupid app to make a report later in my day in seconds, I would say that yes. Yes spending the three hours fighting with try, catch loops was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLDR, noob gets wrekt by pythons immaculate error handling. Check out my project, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ofgrenudo/noparser/tree/main&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;noparser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Vacation</title>
        <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-07-vacation/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 10:32:58 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-09-07-vacation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://unorthodoxdev-bucket-public.s3.amazonaws.com/scorpion-hand.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Vacation" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Im back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ive been gone for a little while now. I went on vacation to mexico for about 21 days to visit friends. I had a blast. Everything there is vastly different than here in the states. Where I live, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0277953600000046&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;if you need anything other than beer&lt;/a&gt; you need to drive about 5-20 minutes to get whatever you need. In Druango Durango Mexico, If I need to go to the store, its about a 5 minute walk to a Ley; The equivalent of a walmart or meijers. If im in the mood for some chips and a soda, theres a conveince store, or Oxxo within 2 to 5 minutes. Hungry for a burger, theres a place that sells hamburgesas down the street. Come on lets walk its only 10 minutes away! I will tell you though, I was a little dissapointed in the hamburgessa. I was expecting a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MULhB5_COAU&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;american hamburger&lt;/a&gt; but instead found, carne asada, a salchica split in two, hamon, lettuce tomatoe, onion, pickles, mayo, mustrard, ketchup all on a bun. It was decent, but wasnt what I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the street from where I stayed was a community center. A place where the community can host classes to teach all kinds of things. On Tuesdays and Thursdays theres karate class. On fridays theres dance class teaching you how to perform traditional Aztecan and Mayan dances. On Mondays and Wednesdays theres Singing Class. Tuesday evening they show you how to use a sowing machine and make dresses. Theres a park, with soccer goals, baskeball hoops, playground equipment, etc available all the time. Theres washers and dryers available for those who need them, etc. Over all the community center is something very strange to me. There arent many things like that in america. The closest I could think of is boys and girls club, but im not even sure thats everywhere in the states and Its most definetly not as flexiable as the community center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over all I really enjoyed my trip and cant wait to go back. But for now, ive got school and work to focus on. Ill attach a few photos below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://unorthodoxdev-bucket-public.s3.amazonaws.com/church.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;church.jpeg&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://unorthodoxdev-bucket-public.s3.amazonaws.com/paraguas.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;paraguas.jpeg&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://unorthodoxdev-bucket-public.s3.amazonaws.com/scorpion-hand.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;scorpion-hand.jpeg&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://unorthodoxdev-bucket-public.s3.amazonaws.com/terrain-two.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;terrain-two.jpeg&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://unorthodoxdev-bucket-public.s3.amazonaws.com/terrain.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;terrain.jpeg&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://unorthodoxdev-bucket-public.s3.amazonaws.com/theater.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;theater.jpeg&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://unorthodoxdev-bucket-public.s3.amazonaws.com/train-car.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;train-car.jpeg&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Advent of Code</title>
        <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-09-advent-of-code/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 15:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-09-advent-of-code/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1606482512676-255bf02be7cf" alt="Featured image of post Advent of Code" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advent of Code is a annual set of Christmas themed programming problem that follow an advent calendar. I have heard about Advent of Code (AoC from now on) before but never committed time or resources to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Struggling to learn C, I decided to go through the AoC content from 2015 to current and complete each of the challenges with at a minimum, attempting to use C. The nice thing about doing the older problems, well really any problem, is that there are plenty of resources around online to help me work through and solve the problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to go through at least one problem a day on my lunch break if not more given time permits and upload it to my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ofgrenudo/AoC&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;github repository&lt;/a&gt;. Depending on how I feel I may produce a write up of the problem, challenges I faced, my resolutions, how I could optimize, etc&amp;hellip; I think that this will be a fun exercise and prep me for when the 2023 AoC comes around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun Fact! I did not know that people could prestige programming problems but I recently learned, that people have prestige AoC. I guess at the end of the day, it is a game :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Network Troubleshooting Methodology</title>
        <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-09-network-troubleshooting-methodology/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 14:17:19 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-09-network-troubleshooting-methodology/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a guide i&amp;rsquo;ve created with some notes I have created while working through the networking+ content. While I do plenty of networking troubleshooting experience, these instructions ensure that I &lt;strong&gt;STOP&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;SLOWN DOWN&lt;/strong&gt; and think about the changes. Something else I enjoy about these instructions is they force me to think more about &lt;em&gt;change&lt;/em&gt; management. Something I need more practice with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gather as much information as possible. If possible, duplicate the problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Break the problem down into meaningful bytes. What steps need to occur and in what order? a lot of people use this step as an opportunity to begin working their way &lt;strong&gt;up&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;down&lt;/strong&gt; the OSI Model identifying the processes that take place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate a few different hypothesis&amp;rsquo;s and the steps needed to take to resolve these issues. Document these issues somewhere publicly where you and your peers can look back at them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you begin making changes, document the steps taken to test your hypothesis and perform one change at a time. After you have completed the change, assess the situation and determine if the change has produced a favorable result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you have confirmed that you have resolved the issue, reach out the customer and confirm that they are seeing the same behavior as you are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document, Document, Document everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Finding Things to Do</title>
        <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-07-finding-things-to-do/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 09:36:33 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-07-finding-things-to-do/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am the ultimate procrastinator. I can never seem to commit, or consider a project done. I have a perpetual train of thought going on when I think of projects or problems. I often wont even start a project, unless I can envision the end. Some people may see this as a good trait, being that I am able to plan the project, and goals out from start to finish instead of aimlessly working on something. Sometimes, I may already have the end goal of my project or problem determined, but my issue is then, finding a way to complete it. Maybe not all the tools are there for me that I hope there would have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately I have been learning C. Not C++, not C#&amp;hellip; C. One thing I learned very quickly with C is that there is no hand holding. If you do not manage your memory, you&amp;rsquo;ve blown your program up. You don&amp;rsquo;t know how to do something, you&amp;rsquo;ve made your project 100 times harder now trying to include some foreign library, versus developing the solution your self. My initial Idea was to create a program, that pulls the API information from the local Transit station, and parses out the information into a pleasant way. This program in rust, hypothetically would be pretty quick, and i&amp;rsquo;ve already got an idea on how I would do it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would start by using &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;github.com/actix/actix&#34; &gt;actix&lt;/a&gt; to pull the API get request. parse the JSON response using &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;serde.rs&#34; &gt;serde&lt;/a&gt;. Then use  &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ratatui-org/ratatui&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;rata-tui&lt;/a&gt; to generate a beautiful text UI for it. All together, given I didn&amp;rsquo;t run into any hiccups, this project would probably be done in maybe~ 2 to 3 days If I used rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After almost a month of running through C projects and experiments. Ive found that, I am absolutely destroyed by the lack of features with C. My first challenge was making a get request to the Transit web api. I eventually resolved that issue using &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://curl.se/libcurl/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;libcurl&lt;/a&gt; which is very terribly documented, and everything is just a pain in the ass to read an understand. But one other issue with using libcurl, is that it requires that the system the program is running on, &lt;strong&gt;contains&lt;/strong&gt; the application curl. That is an issue that I haven&amp;rsquo;t really ran into before when programming with rust. Everything is just code, that compiles to assembler that compiles to binary, that the machine understands and executes. Now i have to add another contingent, an application I cant/don&amp;rsquo;t want to package with my application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I understand why applications ship with  DLLs. Or why the applications have underlying conditions when installing them. Regardless of how I felt about including libcurl, I moved forth and began to deal with my newly found string that contains the response from my API. After many &lt;code&gt;segfault&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;s I&amp;rsquo;ve got to parse this JSON string. Like I stated above, I would simply just use the serde library. But because C doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a JSON library (C was made way before the web, or JSON existed) I need to create my own parser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above two issues, is reason enough for me to understand why some hardcore C developers keep every piece of code they have. Because when they run into the same JSON parsing issue, they can look at the function, or file that they made last time, and implement the same function or file into the new program.Rust and most modern languages have provided such a standard, containing large standard libraries and easy to import and manage 3rd party libraries that It was hard for me to think of a time where that wasn&amp;rsquo;t an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgflip.com/4exi8f.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;based&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing I like the most about C is that it forces me to think. To use my &lt;em&gt;smooth&lt;/em&gt; brain on how to parse a JSON element, what are the rules that JSON employs? How can I connect to a HTTP Web server, on port 80? How can I save the response? All of these thoughts come from a &lt;em&gt;rough&lt;/em&gt; brain. One with ridges and valleys and peaks. Not mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While, I think the Transit app i was planning on building with C was a bit too big for me to handle right now, my plan now is to finish it in Rust, and then In preparation for the 2023 Advent of Code, i would like to begin practicing my C solving those problems. Problems which are small and manageable, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure have plenty of resources online for the language that I will be using. Shoot, I&amp;rsquo;ve even found &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/betaveros/noulith&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a guy who created an entire language, for solving the Advent of Code problems&lt;/a&gt; conveniently in&amp;hellip;. Rust. So while i&amp;rsquo;ve completely changed the way I will handle my next app. I have added a completely other thing that I have dedicated my self to. Finding more things to do, when there is already so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgflip.com/56pjdz.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;smooth brain&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>In dire need of comments.</title>
        <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-01-in-dire-need-of-comments./</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 10:07:32 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-08-01-in-dire-need-of-comments./</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently migrated my website from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ghost.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ghost blog&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt; which is a static site generator compared to the all in one package you get with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ghost.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ghost blog&lt;/a&gt;. One of the reasons I decided to make this change was honestly, I had no need for all of the many features that ghost blog provided. Something like Hugo was simple, and effective. It also allowed me to write my documents in mark down, and store the entirety of it in a git repository. Making the portability of my website insanely simple, compared to managing the ghost blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the features I missed from ghost blog though, was the comment feature. Something I really enjoyed. With some Hugo blogs, they do enable you to add a comment feature, but requires that you have some kind of third party application that you sign up for. That pretty much was a no go for me. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have my self or readers sign up for some ooey gooey third party provider. So because i&amp;rsquo;m lazy, I decided to create my own comment board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ive been learning rust for some time now so I settled on that language. It would be a good proof of concept and really help me get my foot in the door when it comes to getting confidence in the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planning&#34;&gt;Planning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets break down how we are going to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User must reach URL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User inputs the following, username, comment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User submits comment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Program submits comment to database after running it through some checks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comment board is updated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have a general road map there are quite a few things we can extrapolate from this. One, I can already imagine how my data will look. Two, we can create a general rest API from this point forward. Lets start with our data template&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data&#34;&gt;Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to go with sqlite because Im not sure that this website will ever get enough use that I will need to migrate away from an sqlite file. Although if it ever did, im sure it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too much more complicated to migrate to a MariaDB or a full fledged Sql database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general lets get what our data structure will look like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;6
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;7
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-rust&#34; data-lang=&#34;rust&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;ip&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;username&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;timestamp&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;visible&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;int32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll notice there are a few things here that I have added besides the username and comment. One of them being ID. That will be our entry&amp;rsquo;s primary key. I plan on keeping the IP for governance reasons (issue bans, etc), as well as a timestamp, for historical records. The visible key, will be a simple 1 or 0. If it is 1 then it is visible. If it is 0 then it is hidden. Say I get a derogatory or inappropriate comment, I would&amp;rsquo;t want to necessarily delete it these comments should be kept to be referenced to for example for a ban appeal.I would want to especially keep them if it were to say be life threatening etc. So to prevent displaying it, I will switch the visible to 0 and contact or inform the police of said threat. This way, I still have the comment but its not visible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;api&#34;&gt;API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the requirements above, theres a few things we can already build out API wise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/comment/new&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/comment/id/&lt;id&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/comment/ip/&lt;ip&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/comment/username/&lt;username&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building out the API this way also allows us to tailor, how and what we write when we begin to create our program. I now know that I will need quite a few get functions that return data based off of 3 unique queries. I can also identify that I only need one query to create any data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that by now you can very clearly see the benefit of planning your program out, before actually typing any code. This will help you keep from getting lost while creating your program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thats about it for the theory on how this comment board will work. In the future, when i&amp;rsquo;ve got everything figured out. I may look into creating either a tutorial series on what i&amp;rsquo;ve done so far, or create youtube videos (as there are not many tutorials out on youtube for rust quite yet).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Ublock Origin and More</title>
        <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-ublock-origin-and-more/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 21:00:06 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-ublock-origin-and-more/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1496442226666-8d4d0e62e6e9" alt="Featured image of post Ublock Origin and More" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everybody knows about &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ublockorigin.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;uBlock Origin&lt;/a&gt;. The browser extension that blocks ads right? Well most ads. Theres often ads from social medias sites like facebook and twitter that slip through really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I recently learned that uBlock has the capability to extend those block lists. The easiset way to add capabilities to your uBlock is to find these pre made lists of URLs and it should begin to block those ads for you. These are really the same lists that DNS filters like pi-hole use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good website that has some of these lists are &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://easylist.to&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://easylist.to&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browse to the website, and find what ever list you want and then select the button &lt;strong&gt;add it to your blocker.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will open a new tab, and then uBlock will prompt you to subscribe it it. Select &amp;lsquo;Subscribe&amp;rsquo; and then you will be live with that list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Digital Gardens</title>
        <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-digital-gardens/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 20:59:39 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-digital-gardens/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1550948390-6eb7fa773072" alt="Featured image of post Digital Gardens" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;outline&#34;&gt;Outline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-a-digital-garden&#34;&gt;What is a Digital Garden?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place for ideas to grow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A place for critiques.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An exercise in learning in public.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;learn-in-public&#34;&gt;Learn In Public&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Honesty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate Resources that you wish you had.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;work-in-public&#34;&gt;Work In Public&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document Your Self.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document Your Steps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working In Public Forces you to Work your Metacognitive Mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is a digital garden? &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://notes.joschua.io/50&amp;#43;Slipbox/Digital&amp;#43;garden&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://notes.joschua.io/50+Slipbox/Digital+garden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work In Public &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://nesslabs.com/work-in-public&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://nesslabs.com/work-in-public&lt;/a&gt;
Learn In Public &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.swyx.io/learn-in-public&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.swyx.io/learn-in-public&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick Up What They Put Down &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.swyx.io/puwtpd&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.swyx.io/puwtpd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn In Private &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.swyx.io/learn-in-private&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.swyx.io/learn-in-private&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do Rocket Scientists Learn &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.govloop.com/community/blog/how-do-rocket-scientists-learn-aka-knowledge-management-lessons-learned-at-goddard-nasa/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.govloop.com/community/blog/how-do-rocket-scientists-learn-aka-knowledge-management-lessons-learned-at-goddard-nasa/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-digital-garden-1&#34;&gt;What is a Digital Garden?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A digital garden to me is a place for for my ideas, projects, and thoughts to be planted in, and sprout and grow in the future. Besides a personal journal on my computer Ive decided to make it a publicly facing blog. Ive decided to so for a few reasons. A digital garden allows space for critiques from others. I don&amp;rsquo;t know everything, nor do I know the best way to do one thing. Posting things publicly allows for a criticism from netizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As I grow, my notes will grow. They will mature from that seed to a full grown plant later in the future.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://notes.joschua.io/50&amp;#43;Slipbox/Digital&amp;#43;garden&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;(Digital Garden, Joschua)&lt;/a&gt; This is a practice of Working in Public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-in-public&#34;&gt;Working In Public&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://s18798.pcdn.co/motivationlab/wp-content/uploads/sites/6235/2023/02/two-routes-to-the-sr-oof-mot-and-goals.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Studies show that statistically, people are more likely to do stuff if they keep their intentions in private.&lt;/a&gt; But at times though that statement can seem counter intuitive. Often, people share their weight loss publicly on Facebook or Twitter or Instagram. Many report that doing so is a great way to stay motivated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you think about it, some of the reason, people post things online is because it provides a way for you to receive praise along the way. A quote that sticks with me is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Become a documentarian of what you do&amp;rdquo; - Austin Kleon, Author of Show Your Work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becoming a documentarian means that you will develop very quickly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your Metacognition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick Feedback Loops on Content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased Creativity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By documenting your self, you are working your Metacognition. You are working on thinking of your thoughts. Should I have done that? Should I have done this instead. Why did I take that route? Was it because of an experience I had? Working your metacognition and &lt;em&gt;thinking&lt;/em&gt; about your thinking allows for you to quickly determine fallacies in your thought pattern. It also helps you explain in better depth, what you are working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in public also forces you to document not only your thoughts, but also your steps taken to get there. Doing this its self can help you identify un necessary steps and find better work flows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Migrating Ghost Blog Domain Names</title>
        <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-migrating-ghost-blog-domain-names/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 12:20:21 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/p/2023-07-19-migrating-ghost-blog-domain-names/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1628595351029-c2bf17511435" alt="Featured image of post Migrating Ghost Blog Domain Names" /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note! I have migrated away from ghost blog and now manage my site on hugo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason when I was looking up how to change [[domain names]] for my ghost blog, I kept running into recommendations that stated I should just reinstall ghost. I really don&amp;rsquo;t want to do that especially since so much content exists on this server already. It also reminded me that I probably need to take regular backups of the server anyways. Or at least, double book blog posts somewhere just in case! (Truthfully most posts end up in my notebook to begin with, and end up polished on the website). Below are my steps to migrate my blogs DNS record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set your new DNS record, a day in advanced to the IP address of your server. In my case I was migrating from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.unorthodoxdev.net&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://blog.unorthodoxdev.net&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://unorthodoxdev.net&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://unorthodoxdev.net&lt;/a&gt;. I created a ANAME record and allowed it to propagate overnight. In the morning, I did the below steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ghost config url {new_url}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;rm /etc/nginx/sites-enabled/*.conf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ghost setup ssl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ghost restart&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally you want to visit your website and check your cert and go from there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also like to throw in that you might want to remove your ANAME record for whatever your website was before and upgrade it to a CNAME record. CNAME records are really just a redirect to whatever ANAME record you provide it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
