<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes on Unorthodoxdev</title>
    <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/categories/recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recipes on Unorthodoxdev</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 11:31:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://unorthodoxdev.net/categories/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Noodle Soupless (Slow Cooker)</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/dinner/chicken-noodle-soupless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 11:31:24 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/dinner/chicken-noodle-soupless/</guid>
      <description>Notice, that this recipe, requires roughly 7 hours to complete, most of which are waiting on the slowcooker.&#xA;Ingredients Defrosted Chicken Breasts or Thighs (thighs preferred or chicken breasts cut into strips). 2 cans of corn, 3 or fresh cobs. 1 can of cut carrots, 2 fresh carrots. 3 chile poblano peppers. 1/4 cup of cream cheese. Parmesan cheese. (Optional) Mozzarella. Directions Note because this recipie takes so long, its ideal to start this at home on my lunch break, or place the chicken in the morning on low, though ive never tested leaving the crockpot on all day cooking like that, I imagine it should be fine :)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goulash</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/dinner/goulash/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 15:42:37 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/dinner/goulash/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1lb of ground beef. 1 onion (preferably yellow or red). Tomatoes. Bell Peppers. Canned tomato sauce. Noodles (preferably macaroni). 1/2 Cup water. 2-4 cloves of garlic. Oregano Basil Crushed Red Pepper Red Wine (Optional) Instructions Dice the onion and garlic. Throw them both into a large soup pot on medium, medium high. Drop a splash of oil. (you dont need alot of oil because shortly youll be adding greasy beef to the mix.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>French Toast</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/breakfast/french-toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 13:26:19 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/breakfast/french-toast/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients These ingredients make six french toast&amp;rsquo;s.&#xA;4 large eggs. 6 slices of bread. 12 tsp&amp;rsquo;s of cane sugar. 2 tablespoons of heavy whipping cream. Butter. Instructions Begin heating your medium pan, on the stove. Place roughly a teaspoon as needed into the pan to prevent sticking of the sugar as it melts down. In a bowl, crack all 4 large eggs, and add about two tablespoons of heavy whipping cream to the mixture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chilequiles</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/breakfast/chilequiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 15:57:33 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/breakfast/chilequiles/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Tortillas or Tortilla Chips (can be stale) Salsa Egg Ham (optional) Chorizo (optional) Instructions Note if you are opting to use chorizo, please cook it first, then continue these instructions. Add the chorizo around the same time you would add the ham.&#xA;In a pan, set the heat to medium place two tablespoons worth of oil into the pan, and place your tortilla chips, if you are using tortillas, cut them into squares or triangles, and fry them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enchiladas</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/dinner/enchiladas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 15:41:38 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/dinner/enchiladas/</guid>
      <description>Enchiladas are traditionally served stuffed with cheese or potatoes, but in america are commonly found stuffed with chicken. Realistically you can use what ever you want, ive even had carne asada enchiladas&amp;hellip;&#xA;Ingredients Chiles Guajillo Chiles Ancho Garlic Cloves Oregano Salt and pepper Corn Tortillas Queso Fresco Potaoes (optional) Chicken Breast (optional) Cebollya Blanca Vegetable oil Lettuce Sour Cream Instructions Toast all of your chiles on a open flame or pan until hot, maybe burnt.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Mack</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/dinner/chicken-mack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 15:31:25 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/dinner/chicken-mack/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 16 oz. box spiral noodles or elbow noodles. 1 25 oz. bag of chicken strips. 1 pack of bacon strips (optional). Salt and Pepper. Basil. Cheese Sauce 1 stick butter. 2 cups heavy cream. 1/2 cup shredded parmesan cheese. 1 cup mozzarella cheese, freshly shredded. 3/4 cup colby jack cheese, freshly shredded. 2-3 cloves of garlic, minced. Chopped fresh basil. Instructions Begin preheating your oven and prepping a tray to cook your chicken tenders on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gorilla Balls</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/deserts/gorilla-balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 18:26:44 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/deserts/gorilla-balls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 cup packed brown sugar. 1/2 c. butter (cubed). 2 tubes (12 oz each) refrigerated biscuits. 1/2 c. sugar. 1 tbsp ground cinnamon. 1 package (8oz) cream cheese, cut into 20 cubes. Directions In a small microwave-safe bowl, heat brown sugar and butter on high for one minute or until sugar is dissolved. Set aside. Flatten each biscuit into a 3 inch circle. Place cream cheese cube in center. Push the sides of the biscuit around cream cheese and form into ball so biscuit is wrapped all around cream cheese.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cowboy Cookies</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/deserts/cowboy-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 14:06:29 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/deserts/cowboy-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 2 cups flour 1/2 tsp baking powder 1 tsp baking soda 1/2 tsp salt 1/2 cup butter 1/2 cup vegetable oil 1 cup backed light brown sugar 1 cup white sugar 2 eggs 1 tsp vanilla extract 2 cups quick cooking oats 1 cup semi-sweet chocolate chips or other mix-ins Directions Preheat oven to 350 F Mix flour, baking powder, baking soda, and salt together, set aside Cream butter, oil, and sugars together until light and fluffy Add eggs and vanilla and cream again Add oats and flour mixture, mix until almost combined Add mix-ins, mix until just combined Drop by spoonfuls onto un-greased baking sheet, bake 10-12 minutes Nutrition Information Measurement Serving Protein Fiber Calories Fat Carbohydrates Sodium </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tinga</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/dinner/tinga/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 13:57:24 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/dinner/tinga/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Large Yellow Onion. Oil. Stewed Tomatoes (Can be home made or from a can). Chipotle peppers in adobo sauce. Tostadas Sour cream Chicken breasts (Optional) Pineapple Directions In a large pot, begin to boil your chicken. Once your chicken is fully cooked, remove it from the water and allow time for it to cool. Once cool, begin to shred the chicken by hand.&#xA;While the pot of chicken is boiling you could begin to add your tomatoes and chipotle peppers in (if raw and not from a can) to begin boiling, or add it to its own pot and boil that way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andrea&#39;s Chilli Recipe</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/dinner/andreas-chili-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 13:24:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/dinner/andreas-chili-recipe/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 lb ground beef 1 medium onion, chopped 1 green pepper chopped 2 stalks of celery, chopped. 1 can black beans rinsed and drained. 1 can dark red kidney beans rinsed and drained 1 can garbonzo beans, rinsed and drained. 1 can kidney beans in chili sauce (do not drain or rinse these) 1 can corn rinsed and drained 2 cans diced tomatoes Directions Brown beef in skillet over medium heat until no longer pink.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bannana Bread</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/deserts/bannana-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 13:24:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/deserts/bannana-bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 3 1/2 cups of sifted all purpose flour 3 tsp baking powder 1 tsp salt 1 tsp baking soda 2 cups of mashed ripe bananas 2 tsp of lemon juice 3/4 cups of shortening 1 1/2 cup of sugar 3 eggs 3/4 cups of milk 1/2 chopped walnuts or pecans Directions Sift together flour, baking powder, salt, and baking soda, combine bananas and lemon juice. Mix well. Cream together shortening and sugar in a bowl with electric mixer medium speed until fluffy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Breakfast Bars</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/breakfast/blueberry-breakfast-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 13:24:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/breakfast/blueberry-breakfast-bars/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 3/4 cup of sugar 1 cup of butter 4 eggs 1 tsp vanilla extract 3 cups of flour 1 1/2 tsp baking poweder 21 oz blueberry pie filling 1 tbsp butter melted 2 tbsp lemon juice Directions Cream sugar and butter, add eggs and vanilla. Beat well. Ad flour and baking powder, stir until well blended. Spread half of the mixture into a greased 15&amp;quot; x 10&amp;quot; pan. Carefully top with pie filling.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peanut Butter Cereal Bars</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/breakfast/peanut-butter-cereal-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 13:24:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/breakfast/peanut-butter-cereal-bars/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 3 cups miniature marshmallows 3 tsp margarine or butter 1/2 cup peanut butter 3 1/2 cups crispy rice cereal 1 cup uncooked quick oats 1/3 cup mini semi-sweet chocolate chips Directions Combine marshmallows and margarine in a large microwavable bowl. Microwave on high for 15 seconds. Stir; Continue to microwave 1 minute. Stir until marshmallows are melted and mixture is smooth. Add peanut butter. Stir; Add cereal and oats. Stir until well coated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Brunch Casserole</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/breakfast/sunday-brunch-casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 13:24:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/breakfast/sunday-brunch-casserole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1/2lb sliced bacon 1/2 cup of chopped onion 1/2 cup chopped green pepper 12 eggs 1 cup milk 1 package (16 oz) frozen hash brown potatoes thawed. 1 cup (4 oz) shredded cheddar cheese 1 tsp salt 1/2 tsp pepper 1/4 tsp dill weed Directions In a large skillet, cook bacon over medium heat until crispy. Remove to paper towel lined plate to drain. Reserving 2 tbsp of drippings, crumble bacon and set aside.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taco Salad</title>
      <link>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/dinner/taco-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 13:24:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://unorthodoxdev.net/recipes/dinner/taco-salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients 1 head of lettuce, shredded 1 medium onion, chopped 1 lb hamburger browned 2 cups of cheddar cheese shredded 3 medium tomatoes, chopped 1 bag dorites crushed 1/2 to 1 bottle Western French Dressing (8 oz) Directions In a large bowl, layer each ingredient starting with lettuce and ending with tomatoes. Toss with western dressing and crushed doritos just before serving.&#xA;If you are planning for left overs, allow guests to add the doritos and dressing on their own to prevent any soggy nonsense.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
